Nick Pelletier

- Montréal, QC
- github.com/nwpelletier

- (438) 680-1479
- in linkedin.com/in/nwpelletier

Objective

Curious and creative developer driven by a love of problem-solving and thoughtful design. I focus on web technologies and enjoy crafting clean, intuitive experiences. Always learning, I aim to build solutions that are both functional and meaningful.

Professional Experience

Software and Web Developer

CERASP

01/2024 - present | Montreal, QC

- Developing a React-based website using Strapi as a headless CMS to allow easy content generation for the user, and lightweight responsive design across devices
- Worked on Unity VR projects, contributing to the development and optimization of interaction simulations.

Sound Recording Technician

McGill University

01/2020 - 01/2022 | Montreal, QC

- Assisted in recording and production of high-quality audio for various projects and events.
- Operated studio equipment and collaborated with faculty and students to achieve project goals.

Production Assistant

Industrial Light & Magic (ILM)

08/2016 - 08/2018 | Vancouver, BC

- Assisted in the production of visual effects for major film projects, handling support tasks in a fast-paced environment.
- Gained experience in project coordination and creative collaboration.

Skills

Web Development

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node.js

Development Tools and Task Management

Git, Postman, AWS, Trello, Notion, Jira, Figma

Game Development

Unity, C#, FMOD

Education

AEC, Full Stack Development

John Abbott College 01/2023 – 01/2024 | Montreal, QC

Master, Sound Recording

McGill University
09/2019 – 04/2021 | Montreal, QC

Bachelor, Music

University of Ottawa 09/2009 – 04/2013 | Ottawa, ON

Projects

Whisper Ads (Google Chrome Extension)

- Developed a Chrome plugin to subdue or mute autoplay video/ad volume.
- Used JavaScript and Chrome API for seamless extension creation.

Procedural Map Generator (Unity)

Ongoing Personal Project

- Built a random map generation system for games using Kruskal's algorithm to ensure fully connected, programmed in C#.
- Designed for modular 3D environments with roombased structures, supporting replayability and dynamic level design.